provida.org.br 2018-08-12

# Privacy Statement

**Luzern, May 25, 2018**

PRÓ-VIDA Foundation (“We“ or “Us”) is a philanthropic organization that coordinates internationally all the activities of the PRO-VIDA Movement and allows the philosophical knowledge organized by Dr. Celso Charuri to be taken to all places where there are people interested in it.

With its seat in Luzern, Switzerland, PRÓ-VIDA Foundation complies with the strictest international criteria governing approval of this kind of foundation, with proven integrity and testimony in the environment.

We are delighted about your visit to our internet pages and mobile applications (together also referred to as “Online Information”) and about your interest in our organization.

PRO-VIDA Foundation, and PRO-VIDA Movement members listed in Annex I, has a policy to respect and treat with confidentiality all personal data it processes. The below data privacy policy has been established to cover how PRO-VIDA Foundation uses and processes personal information and data. It also informs about data privacy rights that individuals can exercise at any time. Data protection and information security are included in our organization policy.

PRO-VIDA Foundation is the controller responsible for the processing of your data; exceptions are outlined in this data protection notice. Our contact details are as follows:

c/o Aricon Treuhand AG  
Habsburgerstrasse 12  
6002 Luzern, CH  
+41 41 562 57 56  
data-protection@provida.net  

##  Processed categories of data  

The following categories of data are processed:

  * Communication data (e.g. name, telephone, e-mail, address, IP address)

##  Precept  

Personal data consists of all information related to an identified or identifiable natural person, this includes, e.g. names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, date of birth and payment data, which is an expression of a person's identity.

We collect, process and use personal data (including IP addresses) only when there is either a statutory legal basis to do so or you have given your consent to the processing or use of personal data concerning this matter, e.g. by means of registration.

##  Processing purposes and legal bases  

We and our volunteers process your personal data for the following processing purposes:

  * Provision of this Online Information (Legal basis: Justified interest on our part in direct marketing as long as this occurs in accordance with data protection).

  * To determine disruptions/disturbances and for security reasons (Legal bases: Fulfillment of our legal obligations within the scope of data security and justified interest in resolving disruptions/disturbances and in the security of our information).

  * Dispatch of an email newsletter with the recipient’s consent (Legal basis: Consent).

  * Safeguarding and vindication of our rights (Legal basis: Justified interest on our part for the safeguarding and vindication of our rights).

Every time you use the internet, your browser transmits certain information, which we store in so-called log files. We keep log files for the period required by legal regulations and then we delete them afterwards. Log files which need to be maintained for evidence purposes are excluded from deletion until the respective incident has been completely resolved and may, on a case-by-case basis, be passed on to investigating authorities. Log files are also used for analysis purposes (without IP address or without complete IP address).

In log files, the following information in particular is being saved:

  * IP address (internet protocol address) of the terminal device which is being used to access the Online Information;

  * Internet address of the website from which the Online Information has been accessed (so-called URL of origin or referrer URL);

  * Name of the service provider, which is used to access the Online Information;

  * Name of the files or information accessed;

  * Date and time as well as duration of retrieval;

  * Amount of data transferred;

  * Operating system and information on the internet browser used including add-ons installed (e.g., Flash Player);

  * HTTP status code (e.g., “Request successful” or “File requested not found”).

Your personal data is principally forwarded to other organizations of the PRO-VIDA Movement only when required for the fulfillment of a contract or when your consent has been given. Additionally, data may be transferred to other controllers when we are obliged to do so due to statutory regulations or enforceable administrative or judicial orders.

##  General  

Cookies are small text files that are being saved on your computer when an Online Information is visited. In case you access this Online Information another time, your browser sends the cookies' content back to the respective offeror and, thus, allows the re-identification of the terminal device. Reading the cookies allows us to design our Online Information optimally for you and makes it easier for you to use them.

##  Deactivation and deletion of cookies  

When you visit our internet pages, you will be informed in a cookie layer pop up that cookies are being set on our page. In case you decide to block cookies, your browser allows you to deactivate and delete all cookies at all times. To do so, please consult your browser's help functions. This might, however, lead to individual functions no longer being available. Please note that deactivation and deletion of cookies, for technical reasons, only can be set for the browser that was used for. In case you use a different browser or a different terminal device, you must deactivate or delete again.

##  Overview of cookies used by us  

In this section, please find an overview of cookies we use.

a) Absolutely necessary cookies

Certain cookies are necessary so we can securely render our Online Information. This category includes, e.g.:

  * Cookies that identify or authenticate our users;

  * Cookies that temporarily save certain user input (e.g., content of an online form);

  * Cookies that store certain user preferences (e.g., search or language settings);

  * Cookies that store data to ensure the unimpeded playback of video or audio content.

b) Analytical cookies

We use analytical cookies to record the usage behavior (e.g., links clicked, search queries put in) of our users and to evaluate it statistically.

We need statistical information about the usage of our Online Information to design them to be more user-friendly, to perform range measurements, and to perform user experience research. For this purpose, we use the web analysis tools described in this section.

The usage profiles created by these tools using analysis cookies or by evaluating log files do not contain personal data. The tools either do not use user IP addresses at all or shorten them immediately after gathering them.

The tools offerors process data only as processors subject to our directives and not for their own purposes.

In the following, please find information on each tool offeror and how you are able to object to the collection and processing of data through the tool.

Be advised that with regard to tools which use opt out cookies, the opt out function is related to a device or browser and is thus valid for the terminal device or browser used at this time. In case you use several terminal devices or browsers, you must opt out on every device and with every browser used.

Beyond this, you can generally avoid the forming of usage profiles by generally deactivating cookie usage.

Within the scope of our Online Information, you are able to sign up for newsletters. To do so, we use the so-called opt-in procedure, which means that we will only send you a newsletter via e-mail after you have explicitly confirmed the activation of the newsletter service to us. In case you wish to no longer receive newsletters at a later date, you can terminate the subscription at any time by withdrawing your consent. You can withdraw your consent to email newsletters by clicking the link, which is sent in the respective Online Information email, as the case may be. This occurs in the administrative settings.

At any time, you may exercise the following rights with regards to your personal data processed by PRO-VIDA Foundation:

  * Right of access to personal data;

  * Right to rectification, completion or updating of personal data;

  * Right to delete personal data (“right to be forgotten”);

  * Right to unsubscribe from any communication in case no further involvement with PRO-VIDA Foundation.

The point of contact for individuals to exercise the above rights with regards to their personal data is PRO-VIDA Foundation data protection secretary: data-protection@provida.net.

Our volunteers and the companies providing services on our behalf are obliged to confidentiality and to compliance with the applicable data protection laws.

We take all necessary technical and organizational measures to ensure an appropriate level of security and to protect your data that are administrated by us especially from the risks of unintended or unlawful destruction, manipulation, loss, change or unauthorized disclosure or unauthorized access. Our security measures are, pursuant to technological progress, constantly being improved.

Address:

c/o Aricon Treuhand AG  
Habsburgerstrasse 12  
6002 Luzern, Switzerland

We reserve the right to change our security and data protection measures if this is required due to technical development. In such cases, we will amend our data protection notice accordingly. Please therefore observe the current version of our data protection notice, as this is subject to change.

List of PRO-VIDA Movement member associations:

Country/City Association Name

**Argentina/Buenos Aires**  – ASOCIACIÓN FILOSÓFICA DR. CELSO CHARURI DE BUENOS AIRES  
**Argentina/Coronel** Dorrego – ASOCIACIÓN FILOSÓFICA DR CELSO CHARURI DE CORONEL DORREGO  
**Argentina/Mendoza**  – ASOCIACIÓN CIVIL DR. CELSO CHARURI DE MENDOZA – MENDOZA  
**Argentina/Pilar**  – ASOCIACION DR. CELSO CHARURI DE LOS CARDALES – PILAR  
**Argentina/Trelew**  – ASOCIACIÓN FILOSÓFICA DR. CELSO CHARURI DE LA CIUDAD DE TRELEW  
**Colombia/Pereira**  – ASOCIACIÓN FILOSÓFICA DE PEREIRA  
**Bolivia/Santa Cruz de la Sierra**  – ASOCIACIÓN DOCTOR CELSO CHARURI DE SANTA CRUZ  
**Chile/Santiago de Chile**  – ASOCIACIÓN DR. CELSO CHARURI DE CHILE  
**Italy/Latina**  – ASSOCIAZIONE CITTA' DI LATINA DOTT. CELSO CHARURI – ONLUS  
**Italy/Milano**  – ASSOCIAZIONE DOTT. CELSO CHARURI DI MILANO  
**Italy/Rome**  – ROMA ANTARES – ASSOCIAZIONE CULTURALE  
**Italy/Verona**  – ASSOCIAZIONE DOTT. CELSO CHARURI DI VERONA  
**Mexico/Irapuato**  – CUMBRE DE ACULTZINGO 26-601  
**Mexico/Mexico City**  – ESTUDIOS FILOSÓFICOS DE LA CIUDAD DE MÉXICO  
**Portugal/Leiria**  – DESENVOLVIMENTE ASSOCIAÇÃO ESTUDOS FILOSOFICOS DE LEIRIA  
**Portugal/Lisboa**  – ASSOCIAÇÃO DR. CELSO CHARURI DE PORTUGAL  
**Portugal/Porto**  – ASSOCIAÇÃO DE ESTUDOS FILOSÓFICOS DO NORTE  
**Spain/Reus**  – ASOCIACION AMDEFI – REUS  
**USA/New York**  – ASSOCIATION FOR PHILOSOPHCAL STUDIES OF NEW YORK
